Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/nik-ahmad-akram-6b8a6355 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Data Science
Machine Learning
Computer Vision

Certifications

Data Science Specialization
Executive Data Science Capstone
Data Science Capstone
Executive Data Science
Specialization

Publications

Reducing Support Vector Machine complexity by implementing Kalman Filter

Active incremental Support Vector Machine for oil and gas pipeline defects prediction system using long range ultrasonic transducers

Genetic Algorithm as Quadratic Programming Solver for Support Vector Machine

Nik Ahmad Akram

Data Science | Machine Learning | Gardening Kuala Lumpur

Summary

Experienced data science and machine learning practitioner with a demonstrated history of working in industries. Skilled in Data Science, Machine Learning and Image Processing. Strong professional with a Doctor of Philosophy (PhD) focused in Artificial Intelligence from The University of Nottingham Malaysia Campus.

My first Machine Learning application was in 2009 where i applied Support Vector Machine algorithm on ultrasonic sensors data to track the corrosion rates of oil and gas pipeline. The work is documented in a research paper "Nik Zulkepeli, Nik Ahmad Akram & Rajkumar, Rajprasad & Isa, Dino & Hussain, Zakria. On Using Long-Range Ultrasonics to Track Corrosion Rates in Pipelines via Adaptive Machine Learning."

I am enthusiastic about applying data science techniques on various domains to get valuable insights. My career has encompassed building efficient machine learning applications in Non Destructive Testing, Video Surveillance, Satellite Imaging, and Telco data.

Experience

Axiata
Data Scientist
February 2018 - Present (3 years 11 months)
Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

MIMOS Berhad Senior Researcher May 2014 - February 2018 (3 years 10 months)

Education

The University of Nottingham Malaysia Campus

Doctor of Philosophy (PhD), Artificial Intelligence · (2015)

The University of Nottingham Malaysia Campus Master of Engineering (MEng), Electronic and Computer Engineering · (2006 - 2010)